How many times do you need to shuffle a deck of cards to make them truly random?
How much uranium does it take to build a nuclear bomb?
How can you predict the next word in a sentence?
And how does Google know which page you're actually searching for?
Well the reason we know the answer to all of these questions is because of a strange
math feud in Russia that took place over a hundred years ago.
In 1905 socialist groups all across Russia rose up against the Tsar, the ruler of the empire.
They demanded a complete political reform or failing that that he stepped down from power entirely.
This defied the nation into two. So on one side you got the Tsarists, right?
They wanted to defend the status quo and keep the Tsar in power.
But then on the other side you have the socialists who wanted this complete political reform.